A Guide to the Wills from Virginia Land Office records, 1656-1868
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Wills from Virginia Land Office records, 1656-1868
The Library of Virginia
LOI 10
.2 cu. ft. (1 box)
Virginia. Land Office
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Accession LOI 10 transferred by the Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1948.
Scope and Content
These records contain copies of wills that were included as supplemental papers in several series of Land Office records but removed from the records and set up as a separate series. There are no cross references to the specific series from which the wills were removed. The wills are dated between 1656 and 1868; in many cases the copies were made significantly later than the original wills.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into the following series:
I. Wills from Land Office Records, 1656-1868.
The items are arranged alphabetically.
Index Terms
Persons:
Bell, James.; Bentley, Thomas.; Brent, Daniel Carroll; Brinker, Henry.; Brown, Michael.; Carson, Charles S.; Couch, Samuel.; Crutchfield, John.; Digges, Cole.; Duff, Roger.; Ellis, John.; Evans, John.; Farley, Thomas.; Folsom, Israel.; Fontaine, William, 1754-1810.; Garnett, Henry.; Hays, Andrew.; Hays, James.; Hughes, Ralph.; Jenkins, Aaron.; Johnson, Jeoffry.; Johnson, Robert.; Lee, Henry.; Lee, Ann R.; Legrand, Paulina.; McClenachan, John.; Malin, David.; Morton, Hezekiah.; Morton, Pattey.; Nelson, Thomas.; O'Donell, Thomas.; O'Neal, Arthur.; Peachey, Samuel.; Peachey, William.; Peck, John.; Powell, Benjamin.; Price, Leonard.; Read, Edmund, d. 1802.; Sanders, William.; Simmons, Cary.; Sparks, Henry.; Stuart, Alexander.; Thweatt, Thomas.; Travis, Edward.; Vele, Morris.; Walker, Edward.; Watson, Andrew.; Woodlief, Francis E., (Eppes).
Corporate Names:
Virginia. Land Office
Subjects:
Wills. -- South Carolina. -- Charleston.; Wills -- Virginia.
Genre and Form Terms:
State government records.; Wills -- Virginia -- Augusta County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Charlotte County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Culpeper County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Dinwiddie County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Essex County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Floyd County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Frederick County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Giles County.; Wills -- Virgina -- Goochland County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Hampshire County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Hanover County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Hardy County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Henrico County.; Wills -- Virginia -- James City County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Loudoun County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Montgomery County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Northumberland County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Petersburg.; Wills -- Virginia -- Prince Edward County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Prince William County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Richmond County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Rockbridge County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Smyth County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Spotsylvania County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Stafford County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Washington County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Westmoreland County.; Wills -- Virginia -- Wythe County.
Contents List
- Wills from Virginia Land Office records, 1656-1868., Extent: .2 cu. ft.
  Alphabetical
  The dates for each item refer to when will was probated.
  - Bell, James, 1752 May 28. Augusta County.
  - Bentley, Thomas, 1785 Nov. 07. Henrico County.
  - Brent, Daniel Carroll, 1815 Apr. 10. Stafford County.
  - Brinker, Henry, 1772 Aug. 05. Frederick County.
  - Brown, Michael, 1849 Aug. 13. Wythe County.
  - Carson, Charles S., 1815 May 24. Washington County.
  - Couch, Samuel, 1800 Jan. 20. Goochland County.
  - Crutchfield, John, 1819 Feb. 01. Spotsylvania County.
  - Digges, Cole, 1817 Aug. 27. Hanover County.
  - Duff, Roger, 1789 Sep. 29. Frederick County.
  - Ellis, John, 1762 Sep. 07. Frederick County.
  - Evans, John, 1767 Nov. 09. Loudoun County.
  - Farley, Thomas, 1796 Oct. Montgomery County.
  - Folsom, Israel, 1772 Mar. 02. Montgomery County.
  - Fontaine, William, 1810 Oct. 24. Prince William County.
  - Garnett, Henry, 1811 Sep. 16. Essex County.
  - Hays, Andrew, 1786 May 02. Rockbridge County.
  - Hays, James, 1851 June 17. Smyth County.
  - Hughes, Ralph, 1767 Sep. 01. Frederick County.
  - Jenkins, Aaron, 1759 Apr. 04. Frederick County.
  - Johnson, Jeoffry, 1758 Aug. 28. Prince William County.
  - Johnson, Robert, 1763 Nov. 01. Frederick County.
  - Lee, Henry and Ann R., 1840 Nov. 03. Hardy County.
  - Legrand, Paulina, 1845 Mar. 03. Charlotte County.
  - McClenachan, John, 1774 Nov. 16. Augusta County.
  - Malin, David, 1761 Mar. 04. Frederick County.
  - Morton, Hezekiah, 1831 Aug. 15. Prince Edward County.
  - Morton, Pattey, 1834 June 16. Prince Edward County.
  - Nelson, Thomas, 1804 Sep. 25. King William County.
  - O'Donell, Thomas, 1690 Sep. 10. Stafford County.
  - O'Neal, Arthur, 1761 Dec. 08. Hampshire County.
  - Peachey, Samuel, 1795 June 01. Richmond County.
  - Peachey, William, 1803 June 20. Essex County.
  - Peck, John, 1848 Nov. Giles County.
  - Powell, Benjamin, 1808 Nov. 04. Charleston, SC.
  - Price, Leonard, 1772 Mar. 18. Goochland County.
  - Read, Edmund, 1803 Feb. 07. Charlotte County.
  - Sanders, William, 1726 June 29. Westmoreland County.
  - Simmons, Cary, 1868 Apr. 07. Floyd County.
  - Sparks, Henry, 1770 Apr. 19. Culpeper County.
  - Stuart, Alexander, 1758 July 05. Frederick County.
  - Thweatt, Thomas, 1845 Oct. 20. Dinwiddie County.
  - Travis, Edward, 1784 June 13. James City County.
  - Vele, Morris, 1750 June 25. Prince William County.
  - Walker, Edward, 1656 Sep. 20. Northumberland County.
  - Watson, Andrew, 1679 July 09. Stafford County.
  - Woodlief, Francis Eppes, 1810 Feb. 05. Petersburg.